um what is your job I mean really what
is your job so one of our contributors
and community members very very
generously has offered this summary pink
rubber boots says one your job is to
automate yourself out of a job I love
that we're going to return to all of
these two your job is if you see a
problem solve it and three your job is
to make changes you believe in and will
stand by and I want to focus on this
because so many times I've done other
videos on this but as a beginner
especially if you're breaking into
technology um your job is to automate
yourself out of a job your job is to see
a problem and solve it your job is to
make changes that you believe in and
you'll Stand By and that you'll fix and
support you are working for them and I'm
going to take this opportunity to say
that a lot of people who work in
technology are not doing it for those
reasons I know he can get the job but
can he do the job I know he can get the
job but can he do the job I'm not
arguing that with you I'm not arguing
that with you name that movie so
seriously people you are not being paid
to be
entertained I am not
entertained I shall learn next.js and we
shall put forth next.js as our next
solution we don't need that we don't
need
nextjs yes but I want to learn it or how
are you how are you fixing a problem
with next J I'm unclear but this is
something I definitely want to learn you
know what this is the way it goes it's
just so bad I've been in the
system of it the the culture for so long
I am sick and tired I know rant
beginning be beware
of people who do not create Solutions
and who are afraid of losing a job
because they might write code that does
their job better than
them can I agree more with pink rubber
boots your job is literally to create
systems that are going to help replace
you or replace others and I have a story
about this it's very sad story but going
say it
anyway and so while I was at IBM I
helped write some software called
virtual server
administrator and we our job was to I
I've told the story before I'm going to
tell it again so was was to increase the
number of um uh machines that could be
supported by one administrator one
system administrator and we you know we
we created this thing and I wrote a lot
of Pearl and we wrot a lot of python and
I did the whole database and everything
and sure enough I mean I was the only
one coding I've used the story for that
reason because I I was the only one
doing the coding very few of us on the
team could code because they were
operations people I use this story all
the time to talk about why it's
important to learn how to code as well
as I don't know swap out you know raid
five hard drives from your machines on
the race floor there those are
operational sorts of tasks and people
you know the operations people like hey
we don't need to mix so this story goes
with that because I because I learned
how to code I was able to stick around
and not only that I was able to automate
several other people out of their job in
fact I was like one of like three or
four people left out of a team of about
20 because the rest of them all got got
got you know put out they got put out by
the software that remote and so you know
I automated them out of their
jobs I really did I feel horrible about
it but really is it that bad I mean they
can go do other things
right and you know the whole idea of
cicd continuous integration continuous
deployment and that kind of thing is to
make it easier for you to replace your
cell you know and so I really love that
I love that I'm going to add that this
little video to um to the list of videos
about what it means to to go into Tech
lifestyle and what is your actual job
and what is the nature of employment
they did a whole video on the nature of
employment and and frankly I mean the
people that are paying you they're you
know we already talked about creating
trust so that they hired you but once
they hire you then it's more about you
know maintaining that trust and it might
not be working you know as as hard as
you possibly can 9 to5 that's a
different video but it does mean that
you're going to put uh you know you're
going to realize that your job is to see
a problem and to report it and to make
changes where you can and stand by those
changes and um kind of associated with
the virtue of hubris separate video for
that to stand by it you know and to make
sure there's quality in there
so good job